Moses Tseu

Email address: Tseumoses2@gmail.com Tel: +27 (0) 658 031 954

Career Objective

Electrical and Instrument Controls (E&IC) Technician with over 15 years' experience in the

FMCG and Municipality industry. With a comprehensive knowledge of electrical engineering,

design, and codes. Familiar with regulatory standard and procedures of the electrical industry.

A responsible individual who is committed to achieving excellence. Ability to effectively

prioritize and juggle multiple concurrent projects. Excellent attention to details and well

organized. Possess great analytical skills. Always on schedule and budget, able to prioritize

and handle multiple tasks while effectively achieving and exceeding project goals

Key Skills and System Exposure

Troubleshooting in basic PLC

Electrical Maintenance

HV and MV Maintenance

• Refrigeration/ Air conditioning

Microsoft word, Excel and PowerPoint

Instrumentation

Education

Kempton Park Technical Collee (February 1997)

• Electrical Engineering Diploma

Technicol SA

Studying towards GCC

Courses and Certification

• Installation Electrician license (wireman's license)

Professional Experience History

Company: Dairymaid

January 2005 - Till to Date

Position: Electrician

2005 - 2011

Position: Technical Assistance Electrical 2012 – 2018

Position: Electrical and Instrumentation Controls (E&IC) 2018 - Current

Duties

- Repair and maintenance of all electrical machinery
- Ensuring that maintenance of machinery and electrical apparatus (Transformers and switch gears) is completed
- Ensuring that installation is safe and comply with Regulations (SANS 10142 & EMR)
- Coaching electricians on problem solving and implement improvements
- Attending daily reporting meeting and weekly planning
- Upgrading of equipment to meet new standards
- Coordinate projects on energy saving.
- Preparing engineering scope of work for plant electrical projects.
- Supporting the maintenance and operation of plant electrical systems and troubleshooting of electrical and control system problems
- Calibrating of process instruments
- Troubleshooting on PLC
- Install and commissioning of VSD
- Manage and supervision of external contractors

Company: Ekurhuleni metro Municipality

March 1998 – November 2004

Position: Electrician

Duties

- Maintenance and Commissioning of new electrical installations
- Repair LT and HT joints on cable
- Installation of electrical Meters
- Maintenance on street lights and Building Lights
- Electrical maintenance on Municipal buildings as per SANS standards
- Perform switching on HT switch gears

Company: Vaal Reefs mining & exploration

April 1994 - January 1997

Position: Apprentice Electrician

Duties

- Fault finding, design and Wiring of Electrical Panels
- Maintenance of electrical installations
- Maintenance and repairs of electrical motors both surface and underground
- Repair and maintenance of all electrical portable equipment.
- Repair LT and HT surface and underground cables

References

Hendrick Du Preez

Project engineer

082-957-7471

Stanley Makonese

Maintenance Manager

083-534-2255

Calvin Mashau

HR Manager

082-957-7471